Guide to the Alexander Jackson Davis Architectural Drawing Collection 1827-1884 PR 16
New-York Historical Society
- Codwise, David Villa "SUBURBAN VILLA." graphite MC (Item 142a)
  cottage orne "of an Oriental character" with ornamental veranda, not executed, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 108; see #141, 142b, 275n.22-23
- Commercial building, unidentified "Basement plan. No. 1." ink UC (Item 440)
- Commercial Exchange "Private Plan to Keep" graphite UR (Item 307 b verso)
  not executed. inscrp: to gain, Shall find their labors and their hopes are vain Plutarch slightly altered."
- Commercial Exchange "Private Plan to Keep" graphite UR (Item 307 b recto)
  not executed.
- Commercial Exchange "Commercial Exchange" (Item 307 a)
- Commercial Exchange (Item 301 b)
- Commercial Exchange "Commercial Exchange" graphite, ink wash BM (Item 307a)
  Published p. 16 in exhibition catalogue for 1989 Federal Hall "A. J. Davis & American Classicism"
- Commerical building, unidentified (Item [612])
- Complex, unidentified (Item [632])
- Conway, Edmund H. villa "VILLA CONWAY." ink wash LL-LR (Item 101)
  proposed site unknown, no evidence of execution, Peck, Alexander Jacksonb Davis, 107
- Cottage, Tudor "TUDOR COTTAGE" watercolor LC (Item 147)
- Cottage, Tudor "First study Tudor Cottage Newark NJ" ink graphite UR (Item 288 recto)
- Cottage, Tudor "East Side" ink, graphite BM (Item 288 verso)
- Cottage, unidentified (Item 151)
- Cottage, unidentified (Item 471)
- Cottage, unidentified (Item 472)
- Cottage, unidentified (Item 160)
- Cottage, unidentified (Item 145 verso)
- Country church or chapel, Gothic, unidentified (Item 492)
- critics on Dover Palace; information on France and Europe "On Dover Palace" graphite UC; "France" (Item [631 verso])
- Custom House, New York "Custom House, New York. Designed by Ithiel Town and Alexander Jackson Davis, Architects" "Custom House. N.Y. Plan of the Principal Floor Shew (Item 17)
  later alterations in design make print different from actual building
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences" "RURAL DESIGNS. ADVERTISEMENT." NA UC (Item 275n.15)
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences" "RURAL RESIDENCES, ETC. CONSISTING OF DESIGNS, ORIGINAL AND SELECTED, COTTAGES, FARM-HOUSES, VILLAS, AND VILLAGE CHURCHES: WITH BRIEF EXPLANAT (Item 275n.1)
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences" (Item [614])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences" (Item [615])
  alterations in graphite visible on plan
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences", Advertisement "RURAL DESIGNS. ADVERTISEMENT." NA UC (Item [626c])
  see also drawings #[626a-u]; [614]-[625]; [627a-l]; [628a-k]
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences", Advertisement "RURAL DESIGNS. ADVERTISEMENT." NA UC (Item [627c])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences", content list "CONTENTS" graphite UC (Item [631 recto])
  for "Rural Residences", see #[614]-[625]; [626a-u]; [627a-l]; [628a-k]
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences", cover (Item [626u])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences", Cover "RURAL RESIDENCES, ETC." (Item [628a])
  see also #[626b-u]; [614]-[625]; [627a-l]; [628a-k]
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences", cover (Item [627l])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences", cover (Item [628k])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences", Cover "RURAL RESIDENCES, ETC." (Item [626a])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences", Cover "RURAL RESIDENCES, ETC." (Item [627a])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences", specifications "SPECIFICATIOPN OF THE MATERIALS AND WORK REQUIRED FOR BUILDING A DWELLING HOUSE" NA UL-UR (Item [616 recto])
  see also #[617]-[622]
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences", specifications "CONDITIONS For the Performance of the several Works in the respective Trades, as set forth in, and according to the accompanying SPECIFIC (Item [622])
  4 pages document; see also #[616]-[621]
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences", specifications for brick-layer "Brick-layer." NA UL (Item [618 recto])
  see also #[616]-[622]
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences", specifications for brick-layer (Item [618 verso])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences", specifications for brick-layer and plasterer "Plasterer." NA ML (Item [619 recto])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences", specifications for carpenter "Carpenter." NA UL (Item [619 verso])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences", specifications for carpenter (Item [620 recto])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences", specifications for carpenter (Item [620 verso])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences", specifications for carpenter and plumber "Plumber." NA ML (Item [621 recto])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences", specifications for excavator "Excavator." NA UL (Item [616 verso])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences", specifications for mason "Mason." NA UL (Item [617 recto])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences", specifications for mason (Item [617 verso])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences", specifications for plumber, glazier, painter, bell hanger "Galzier." NA UL; "Painter." NA ML; "Bell Hanger." NA LL (Item [621 verso])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences", Title page "RURAL RESIDENCES, ETC." NA UL-UR (Item [626b])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences", Title page "RURAL RESIDENCES, ETC." NA UL-UR (Item [627b])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences", Village School-House (Item [626t])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences", Village School-House (Item [628j])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences"/Codwise, David Villa "COTTAGE ORNE. DESIGNED FOR DAVID CODWISE, ESQUIRE." NA UL; "VILLA, DESIGNED FOR DAV. CODWISE. ESQ.- BY A. J. DAVIS, ARCt." NA MC-MR (Item 142b)
  extract from Davis publication "Rural Residences", 1837; see Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 108; see also #141, 142a, 275n.22-23
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences"/Parsonage "PARSONAGE" ink wash MC (Item 221)
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Alger, Charles C. House "RESIDENCE OF C. C. ALGER, Esq. DOWNING PLACE, HUDSON RIVER" NA UC (Item [624])
  probably a print for a planed re-edition of "Rural Residences"; Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 115; see also #275n, [614], [615], [623], [625]
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": American Cottage "AMERICAN COTTAGE No 1" NA MC (Item [628g])
  see also drawings #[626a-u]; [614]-[625]; [627a-l]; [628a-k]; additions visible in ink (plans)
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": American Cottage "AMERICAN HOUSE." NA UC (Item [626p])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": American Cottage "AMERICAN COTTAGE No 1" NA MC (Item [626q])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": American Cottage "AMERICAN HOUSE." NA UC (Item [628f])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Codwise, David Cottage "COTTAGE ORNE. DESIGNED FOR DAVID CODWISE, ESQUIRE." (Item [626d])
  see also drawings #[626a-u]; [614]-[625]; [627a-l]; [628a-k]; villa not executed, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 108
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Codwise, David Cottage "VILLA, DESIGNED FOR DAV. CODWISE, ESQ.- BY A.J.DAVIS, ARCHt." NA ML-MR (Item [626e])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Codwise, David Cottage "COTTAGE ORNE. DESIGNED FOR DAVID CODWISE, ESQUIRE." (Item [627d])
  see also drawings #[626a-u]; [614]-[625]; [627a-l]; [628a-l]; villa not executed, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 108
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Codwise, David Cottage "VILLA, DESIGNED FOR DAV. CODWISE, ESQ.- BY A.J.DAVIS, ARCHt." NA ML-MR (Item [627e])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Codwise, David Villa "COTTAGE ORNE. DESIGNED FOR DAVID CODWISE, ESQUIRE." NA UC (Item 275n.20)
  see also drawings #275n.21, 141, 142a-b
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Codwise, David Villa "VILLA, DESIGNED FOR DAV. CODWISE, ESQ.- BY A. J. DAVIS, ARCHt." NA MC (Item 275n.21)
  see also drawings #275n.20, 141, 142a-b
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Davis, Julia Jackson House, Kirri Cottage "KIRRI COTTAGE, NEWARK, NEW JERSEY" NA LC (Item [623])
  probably a print for a planed re-edition of "Rural Residences"; Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 113; see #275n, [614], [615], [624], [625]
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Donaldson, Robert Estate, Blithewood "GATE-HOUSE IN THE RUSTIC COTTAGE STYLE." NA UL-UC (Item 275n.16)
  remodeling of house into bracketed cottage orne (1836-1851), Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 109; see also #275n.17
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Donaldson, Robert Estate, Blithewood "GATE-HOUSE IN THE RUSTIC COTTAGE STYLE." NA MC (Item 275n.17)
  remodeling of house into bracketed cottage orne (1836-1851), Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 109; see also #275n.16
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Donaldson, Robert House, Blithewood "VILLA IN THE ENGLISH COLLEGIATE STYLE." NA UC (Item [627h])
  see also drawings #[626a-u]; [614]-[625]; [627a-l]; [628a-k]; villa not executed, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 107
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Donaldson, Robert House, Blithewood "A RESIDENCE IN THE ENGLISH COLLEGIATE STYLE BY A.J. DAVIS." NA ML-MR (Item [626i])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Donaldson, Robert House, Blithewood "VILLA IN THE ENGLISH COLLEGIATE STYLE." NA UC (Item [626h])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Donaldson, Robert House, Blithewood "A RESIDENCE IN THE ENGLISH COLLEGIATE STYLE BY A.J. DAVIS." NA ML-MR (Item [626i])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Donaldson, Robert House, Blithewood, Gate-House "GATE-HOUSE IN THE RUSTIC COTTAGE STYLE." NA UC (Item [626l])
  see also drawings #[626a-u]; [614]-[625]; [627a-l]; [628a-k]; Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 109
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Donaldson, Robert House, Blithewood, Gate-House "GATE-HOUSE IN THE RUSTIC COTTAGE STYLE." NA ML-MR (Item [626m])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Donaldson, Robert House, Blithewood, Gate-House "GATE-HOUSE IN THE RUSTIC COTTAGE STYLE." NA UC (Item [628b])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Donaldson, Robert House, Blithewood, Gate-House "GATE-HOUSE IN THE RUSTIC COTTAGE STYLE." NA ML-MR (Item [628c])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Farmer's House "FARMER'S HOUSE." NA UC (Item 275n.18)
  see also drawing #275n.19
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Farmer's House "FARMER'S HOUSE." NA MC (Item 275n.19)
  see also #275n.18
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Farmer's House "FARMER'S HOUSE." NA UC (Item [626f])
  see also drawings #[626a-u]; [614]-625]; [627a-l]; [628a-k]
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Farmer's House "FARMER'S HOUSE." NA UC (Item [627f])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Farmer's House "FARMER'S HOUSE." NA MC (Item [627g])
  see also drawings #[626a-u]; [614]-[625]; [627a-l]; [628a-k]; alterations visible on plans in ink and graphite
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Farmer's House "FARMER'S HOUSE." NA MC (Item [627g])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Haskell, Llewellyn House, Eyrie "EYRIE." ink MC (Item [625])
  probably a print for a planed re-edition of "Rural Residences"; Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 115; see also #275n., [614], [615], [623], [624]
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Villa in the English Collegiate Style "VILLA IN THE ENGLISH COLLEGIATE STYLE." NA UC (Item 275n.24)
  see also drawing #275n.25
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Villa in the English Collegiate Style "A RESIDENCE IN THE ENGLISH COLLEGIATE STYLE BY A. J. DAVIS." NA MC (Item 275n.25)
  see also drawing #275n.24
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Villa in the oriental Style "VILLA IN THE ORIENTAL STYLE." NA UC (Item 275n.22)
  see Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 108; see also drawings #275n.23, 141, 142a-b
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Villa in the oriental Style "VILLA IN THE ORIENTAL STYLE." NA MC (Item 275n.23)
  see Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 108; see also drawings #275n.22, 141, 142a-b
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": villa in the oriental style "VILLA IN THE ORIENTAL STYLE." NA ML-MR (Item [626o])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": villa in the oriental style "VILLA IN THE ORIENTAL STYLE." NA UC (Item [626n])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": villa in the oriental style "VILLA IN THE ORIENTAL STYLE." NA ML-MR (Item [628e])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": villa in the oriental style "VILLA IN THE ORIENTAL STYLE." NA UC (Item [628d])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Village Church "DESIGN FOR A VILLAGE CHURCH." NA MC (Item [626k])
  see also drawings #[626a-u]; [614]-[625]; [627a-l]; [628a-k]; additions visible in ink and graphite
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Village Church "VILLAGE CHURCH." NA UC (Item [626j])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Village Church "VILLAGE CHURCH." NA UC (Item [627j])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Village Church "DESIGN FOR A VILLAGE CHURCH." NA MC (Item [627k])
  see also drawings #[626a-u]; [614]-[625]; [627a-l]; [628a-k]; additions visible in ink
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Village School "VILLAGE SCHOOL-HOUSE." NA UC (Item [626r])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Village School "DESIGN FOR A MODEL SCHOOL HOUSE." NA MC (Item [626s])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Village School "VILLAGE SCHOOL-HOUSE." NA UC (Item [628h])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences": Village School "DESIGN FOR A MODEL SCHOOL HOUSE." NA MC (Item [628i])
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences"; American Cottage "AMERICAN COTTAGE No. 1" NA MC (Item 359)
  alterations visible on plan
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences"; Farmer's house "FARNER'S HOUSE." NA MC (Item 358)
  alterations visible on first floor plan
- Davis Book, "Rural Residences"; Villa in the oriental style "VILLA IN THE ORIENTAL STYLE." NA MC (Item 357)
- Davis, Charles A. House "l. First Floor ll. Second Floor lll. Third Floor." watercolor, ink, graphite BR-UR (Item 243)
  Only executed commission for Grammercy Park. Built for C.A. Davis (not related) who owned entire west side & 1 of first park trustee. Demolished 1912
- Davis, Charles A. House "Study for Chas. A. Davis Front on Grammery Park" ink, graphite (Item 243)
  Only executed commission for Grammercy Park. Built for C.A. DAvis (not related) who owned entire west side & 1 of first park trustee. Demolished 1912
- Davis, Charles A. House (Item 243g)
- Davis, Charles A. House "Dwelling. Grammery Park. N.Y. Ch. Aug. Davis Park Front" ink, graphite BM (Item 243a recto)
  Only executed commission for Grammery Park. Built for C. A. Davis (not related) who owned entire west side & 1 of first park trustee. Demolished 1912
- Davis, Charles A. House "Design No. 1 First Study B.1.2" ink, watercolor UR (Item 243b)
  Only executed commission for Grammery Park. Built for C. A. Davis (not related) who owned entire wend side & 1 of first park trustee. Demolished 1912
- Davis, Charles A. House (Item 243c)
- Davis, Charles A. House "Cross Section thro' Drawing-room. 1845. Charles A. Davis. Grammery Park" ink, graphite UM (Item 243e)
  Only executed commission for Grammery Park. Built for C.A. Davis (not related) who owned entire west side & 1 of first park trustee. Demolished 1912
- Davis, Charles A. Residence "Design, No. 1. First study B. 1. 2" ink, watercolor UR (Item 243h)
  demolished 1912. Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 112.
- Davis, Charles Augustus House "Dwelling, Charles Augustus Davis, Grammery Park, 20 St." watercolor, graphite BL-BR. "Second Floor" "Basement" ink, graphite UR-BR (Item 243b)
- Davis, Julia Jackson House, Kirri Cottage (Item 053 verso)
  additions 1854 and 1857, demolished ca. 1897, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 113
- Davis, Julia Jackson House, Kirri Cottage "KIRRI COTTAGE, NEWARK, NEW JERSEY" NA MC (Item 275n.30)
  bound with "Rural Residences"; built 1847-1849; addition 1854 and 1857, demolished c. 1897, Peck, Alexander Jackson DaAvis, 113
- Davis, Julia Jackson House, Kirri Cottage "Study on Keri Cot." graphite LR (Item 269c)
  built 1847-49; additions 1854, 1857; demolished ca. 1897, Peck, ALexander Jackson Davis, 113; see also drawings #269a-d
- Davis, Julia Jackson House, Kirri Cottage (Item 269a verso)
  built 1847-1849; additions 1854, 1857; demolishd ca. 1897, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 113; see also drawings #269b-d; alterations visible
- Davis, Julia Jackson House, Kirri Cottage "STUDY FOR KERI COT, SO NAMED FROM A JAPAN TREE." ink LL-LR (Item 269a recto)
- Davis, Julia Jackson House, Kirri Cottage "Keri Cottage, Newark 2d story as executed." ink LL; "Study for an addition to the Keri Cot." ink MR (Item 269b)
- Davis, Julia Jackson House, Kirri Cottage "Keri Cottage, Newark 2d story as executed." ink LL; "Study for an addition to the Keri Cot." ink MR (Item 269b)
- Davis, Julia Jackson House, Kirri Cottage/Design for two Dwelling Houses in Tudor Style "KIRRY." watercolor UR; "Plan for two dwellinggs, in Tudor Gothic Style." ink LL (Item 269)
  Kirri built in 1847-49; additions 1854, 1857; demolished ca. 1897, Peck, ALexander Jackson Davis, 113; see also drawings #269a-c
- Design for an Academy of Arts Art Museum (Item 10)
  fairly detailed drawing, illustrated in Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, American Architect p. 34
- Devil, Daniel House "1851. See Journal, page 124. Study on Dan. Devlin, Manhattanville." (Item 95)
  New York (State)
  Execution uncertain; either executed with substantial changes or superseded by a design by another architect. Demolished.
- Donaldson, James Cottage "Cot. for J.D. enlarged" ink, graphite BL, "Second Story No. 3" ink, BR (Item 273c)
- Donaldson, James Cottage "For James Donaldson." ink, graphite BL (Item 273)
- Donaldson, James Cottage "Davis for James Donaldson" ink, graphite BL "English farm Cottage. $1000.00" ink, graphite BR (Item 273e)
  This version not built. Italiante version built still extant although altered
- Donaldson, James Cottage "Gate Lodge to farm for James Donaldson." ink, graphite UL-UR. "Cottage, or gate reduced" ink, graphite BL "Second, or attic" ink, graphite BR (Item 273)
  Italiante version of building extant although altered, gothic revival version not built
- Donaldson, James Gatehouse "No. 3 Second Story Plan. Small cot, or garte house. for Jas Donaldson. 43 V av. N.Y." ink, graphite BM (Item 273b)
  Extant altered, two design version Italianate built, gothic revival not built
- Donaldson, Robert House "For Robt. Donaldson, then at Fishkill" ink, graphite BM-BR (Item 268a)
  Beacon (N.Y.)
  Not built. Drawing reworked later on.
- Donaldson, Robert House "Plan made for a country villa near Fishkill N.Y. by Alex. J. Davis. Architect" ink, graphite BL-BR (Item 268b)
  Not building. Some reworking of drawing later on.
- Donaldson, Robert Residence "PRINCIPAL FLOOR" ink wash MC-MR (Item 375)
  not executed, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 107
- Doric capitals, study of ancient temples "A PARALLEL OF DORIC CAPITALS" NA ML; "TWO CAPITALS OF COLUMN WITH DORIC ANTA CAPITALS" NA LC (Item 482)
  details are from greek temples in Italy and Greece
- Doric capitals, study of ancient temples "A PARALLEL OF DORIC CAPITALS" NA ML; "TWO CAPITALS OF COLUMNS WITHW DORIC ANTA CAPITALS" NA LC (Item 438 verso)
- Double house, unidentified (Item 474)
  see also drawing #473
- Double house, unidentified (Item 473)
  see also drawing #474
- Double house, unidentified "FRONT." ink MC; "REAR" ink LL (Item 432)
- Double house, unidentified (Item 167)
- Double house, unidentified "Plan for two houses" ink LL-LR (Item 169b)
  see also drawing #168
- Double house, unidentified "Plan for two houses" ink LL-LC (Item 168)
  see also drawing #169b
- Double house, unidentified (Item 401)
  on verso of a New York Post advertisement
- Double houses, two-story, unidentified (Item 560)
- Double town house, unidentified "Plan for two houses on a corner lot. 50 x 70" ink UC (Item 410)
- Double town house, unidentified "SIDE." ink LL; "FRONT." ink LC; "FRONT." ink LR (Item 178)
- Douglas Club House "Entrance Floor Douglas Club 14th St." (Item 312 a recto)
- Douglas Club House "Douglas Club House" LC ink (Item 312 a verso)
- Douglas Club House "Douglas Club House" graphite UC (Item 312 c)
- Dr. Hull, Amos G. Gatehouse "GATE-HOUSE" watercolor LC (Item 103)
  gatehouse and gate demolished in 1960s; watch turret extant, design for a Norman Romanesque villa not executed, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 112
- Dr. Osgood's Church (Item 188)
- Drawings list "No of Library Design" (Item 591)
  written on verso of a letter by Theo. Hertwig dated December 16, 1878;this list refers to drawings #001a, 005, 047, 052, 053, 055-59, 062-063
- Durand, Cyrus House "Design for Mr. Durand 1st floor 10 2nd floor 9" (Item 90)
  Irvington (N.J.)
  enlarged 1880s, demolished 1925.
- Dutch Reformed Church, Newburgh "D. Church. Newburgh" ink LR (Item 196)
  extant, dome removed ca. 1850, enlarged by George Harney, now in bad disrepair. Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 108.
- Early English Gothic Church, on 4th Avenue "Early English Gothic." ink UL (Item 222 recto)
  see also drawings #222 verso and 223; alterations visible
- Early English Gothic Church, on 4th Avenue "Basement. D. " graphite MR (Item 222 verso)
  see also drawings #222 recto and 223
- Early English Gothic Church, on 4th Avenue "Plan exhibiting Basement, principal, & gallery." ink UL-UR (Item 223)
  see also drawings #222 recto-verso
- Elliott, H. H., House "Principal Floor H. H. Elliott, c. 18th & Vth Avenue" watercolor, ink, BR (Item 264 recto)
  part of a pair of townhouses for Elliott and Robert C. Townsend.
- Elliott, H. H., House "Mode adopted by H. H. E." watercolor UL (Item 264 verso)
  part of a pair of townhouses for Elliot and Robert C. Townsend. demolished
- Ellwanger, George Villa "NORTH." ink LC (Item 124)
  Rochester (N.Y.)
  not executed, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 117; see also drawing #415
- Emerson, Wm. House "For a Suburban Residence. A. Study" ink graphite BM "Wm. Emerson" graphite BR (Item 263b)
  built version. demolished
- Emerson, Wm. House "First Study for Wm. Emerson. Staten Isl. 1846, A. J. Davis Arc" watercolor, graphite, BR (Item 263a)
  gothic revival design not executed, house built in greek revival style. Demolished
- "ENGLISH VILLA" ink MC "ENGLISH VILLA" ink MC (Item 462)
  notes in graphite on verso of tertiary support related to Hesiod classification of arts and to greek mythology
- Erectchum "ERECTHEION WESTERN END." watercolor LC (Item 570)
  record and restauration
- Etruscan study for an Italianate Villa (Item 138b)
  See also 138a, 139, 140
- Etruscan villa "Etruscan Villa" graphite UL (Item 144)
  see also drawing #145, 138a-b, 112
- First Mercantile Library "For the First Mercantile Library" ink BL-BM (Item 348)
  wm: "JWhatman" BR; J. Davies notes: Example of very early design before Davis interested in Greek Revival
- Five dwellings and auditory "Five Dwellings and Auditory" ink, graphite CL (Item 247)
- Folder front page "DAN. BUTTERFIELD. N.Y./JOHN RUTHERFORD, N.J./GEORGE MERRITT." ink UC-MC (Item 539)
- Four city houses "4 City houses" graphite LR (Item 407)
  architectural notes on verso
- Fox, Samuel M. House "DESIGN FOR A VILLA IN THE POINTED STYLE" ink wash LC (Item 139)
  Bronx (New York, N.Y.)
  probably built, demolished, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 110
- Fragment of unidentified possibly apartment plan/circular building (Item 466)
  drawn on verso of front page of "Catalogue of the extensive and valuable library of the late Justus McKinstry, esq.", dated 1851
- Gardener's House, Blithewood "Gardenor's House, Blithewood" ink, graphite BR (Item 273a)
  Annandale-on-Hudson (N.Y.), Barrytown (N.Y.)
  Prototype for American Gothic revival cottage, no longer extant part of Robert Donaldson estate, only one building still standing now Bard College.
- Geographical Hall "Geographical Hall" ink, graphite BL-BR (Item 61)
- Geographical Science Library "House on corner 20th St & Grammercy Park" ink UL-UR (Item 277 recto)
  building type con't: societies' buildings. House originally built in 1845 for owner C. A. Davis by A. J. Davis
- Geographical Society "Geographical Society Museum and Library" ink, watercolor, graphite UL-UR (Item 060 recto)
- Geographical Society (Item 063 verso)
  see 63 recto
- Geographical Society "Entrance, or First Floor" (Item 066a verso)
- Geographical Society "Second Floor" ink, graphite BM (Item 066b verso)
- Geographical Society "Study for the Geog. So.c" ink, graphite BM (Item 066c recto)
- Geographical Society (Item 062 verso)
- Geographical Society "Hall for the Geographical Society" watercolor graphite UM (Item 063 recto)
  see also 63 verso